WAYNE YOUNG

LEARNER | ACHIEVER | ANALYTICAL | RESPONSIBILITY | INTELLECTION

SUMMARY

Technology Professional with proven success in product management, software development, product delivery and customer success in IoT, Smart Buildings, Digital Twin and Workforce Automation domains. Proactive manager with 15 years Agile development experience. Servant Leader who works well with all internal and external stakeholders to build collaborative, positive and transparent teams. Diverse, broad background that encompasses exceptional work ethic and technical ability. Noted for leadership skills, problem solving, and ability to build and deliver large, complex systems within budget and on schedule. Enjoys understanding client needs and working together to identify solutions to ensure client success and value.

CONTACT

PHONE:

214.316.2774 (C)

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wayneyoung-1190301/

EMAIL:

wayne@rwysolutions.com

SKILLS

- ✓ SAFe Agile Certified PO/PM
- ✓ Business Analysis
- ✓ Requirements Analysis
- ✓ SaaS
- ✓ DevOps / Azure / AWS / SQL
- ✓ BIM / 3D Visualization / Autodesk
- ✓ Building Automation Systems
- ✓ Written & Verbal Communication
- ✓ Stakeholder Management
- ✓ Account Management
- ✓ Defect Resolution
- ✓ Product Roadmap Development
- ✓ Workforce Management
- ✓ AI/ML

EDUCATION

Shepherd University

Shepherdstown, WV, USA

Bachelors of Science

Business Administration (Major) Computer Science (Minor)

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Product Owner

Sep 2023 – Present

Flexion Inc

- ✓ Built foundational components to extract and transform Salesforce data into a Databricks consolidated data repository to enable advanced analytics of healthcare quality data
- ✓ Integrated Salesforce with Splunk, AppOmni, and Slack for proactive vulnerability management, event logging, and monitoring
- ✓ Streamlined deployment pipeline, significantly reducing release cycle times and minimizing disruptions, directly enhancing the reliability of critical healthcare services
- ✓ Enabled secure and intuitive SSO integrations with Identity Management and Provider systems, leading to improved user access experiences and reducing support incidents related to access issues
- ✓ Proactively identified and mitigated security vulnerabilities, effectively safeguarding sensitive data and reinforcing its standing in secure healthcare service delivery
- ✓ Reduced potential downtime and operational costs by establishing robust prevention and incident management protocols, enabling focus on core mission objectives without interruption
- ✓ Accelerated project delivery and innovation timelines through agile deployment practices combined with integrated security protocols, enabling faster outcomes without compromising data protection
- ✓ Certified SAFe Agile Technical Product Owner
- ✓ Technologies Used: Agile Project Management, Salesforce, SOQL, Databricks, Python, Jira, Confluence, SQL, DevOps, Security, AWS, Terraform, Security Hub, Splunk, Snyk, Megalinter, AppOmni, Postman

Senior Technical Product Owner

June 2022- Aug 2023

Johnson Controls

- ✓ Facilitated global teams of engineers, architects, and IT professionals to deliver the OpenBlue Cloud Platform which included Digital Twin, 3D visualization, IoT sensor telemetry data for monitoring energy usage, alarms, video and predictive analysis
- ✓ Conducted Agile ceremonies, such as sprint planning, daily standups, and retrospectives, to promote effective teamwork and project execution
- ✓ Decomposed complex project requirements and use cases into actionable features, user stories, and acceptance criteria

CONTACT

PHONE: 972.377.2526 (H) 214.316.2774 (C)

EMAIL:

wayne@rwysolutions.com

SKILLS

- ✓ JIRA
- ✓ Confluence
- ✓ Scrum
- ✓ Postgres/GraphQL
- ✓ Postman
- ✓ Oracle
- ✓ SQLServer
- ✓ Salesforce
- ✓ Autodesk Forge
- ✓ Python
- ✓ IoT
- ✓ Meter Data Management
- ✓ Energy
- ✓ Water
- ✓ AMI / AMR
- ✓ APIs
- ✓ GitHub
- ✓ Databricks

- ✓ Led SAFe Agile Transformation process for OpenBlue Cloud Platform team utilizing Jira, Confluence and Miro
- ✓ Certified SAFe Agile technical product owner
- ✓ Collaborated with product managers and business analysts to define and deliver product roadmap
- ✓ Familiar with building automation systems and technologies including BACNet, Modbus, PLCs, OpenBlue Enterprise Manager, Cloud, Bridge, Metasys, and others
- ✓ Created Epics, User Stories, Defects, Spikes and prioritized, maintained and updated agile backlog list in Jira
- ✓ Conducted sprint planning, backlog refinement, retrospective ceremonies
- ✓ Technologies used: Jira, Confluence, Miro, GitHub, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Postman, Insomnia, TypeScript, NodeJS, Angular, Jira, GitHub, Autodesk Forge, BIM360, ACC, SAFe Agile

Partner Executive

Jan 2020- June 2022

Trimble E-Builder

- ✓ Partner Sales Executive responsible for winning new business, executing on existing business and expanding partner capabilities with E-Builder Construction Program Management SaaS solution
- ✓ Performed Key Sales and Account Management functions for major client/partner AEC firms
- ✓ Expanded utility client relationships and closed new business
- ✓ Developed strategic plans, lead pursuits and negotiated and managed contracts and Enterprise License Agreements
- ✓ Identified and pursued new client, partner and opportunity development initiatives
- ✓ Operational and strategic liaison with AEC partners and leads pursuits and engagements across North America

Director, Water Technology Sales & Development Dec 2015 – Oct 2019 iHydrant.com (Nighthawk/McWane)

- ✓ Led agile product development of innovative real-time water pressure network monitoring solution (iHydrant)
- ✓ Utilized Jira to create Epics, User Stories, Defects, Spikes and to prioritize, maintain and update product backlog list
- ✓ Managed the implementation of SaaS iHydrant complex projects for multiple clients
- \checkmark Instrumental in developing and implementing mobile and webbased software/hardware solutions
- ✓ Worked closely with manufacturing to ensure ontime delivery of hardware technology
- ✓ Delivered successful pilots with San Francisco Water, Redmond, Bend, SCWD and others
- ✓ Closed large, complex SaaS deal with Los Angeles Department of Water & Power
- ✓ Identified new uses of GPS, LTE and IoT sensor technology
- ✓ Prioritized, maintained and updated agile product backlog list Technologies used: Agile, Jira, .NET, CSS/HTML5, JavaScript, NodeJS, Angular, SQL Server, Jira, GitHub, GPS, LTE

Clevest, Inc.

- ✓ Managed an Application Development, Delivery and Support team (Developers, Analysts and Testers)
- ✓ Closed complex solution sales with largest IOUs in U.S. including AEP, FirstEnergy, Eversource, Consumers, TECO and others
- ✓ Increased product line sales 3X after acquisition from Neptune Technology Group
- ✓ Partnered with Trimble to build new AMR ruggedized handheld
- ✓ Successfully managed FirstEnergy and Allegheny Energy merger of multiple enterprise systems
- ✓ Sold solution offerings to executive-level decision makers
- ✓ Technologies used: .NET, CSS/HTML, JavaScript, SQL Server, PL/SQL, Oracle, PowerBuilder, C++, ESRI, GPS

Development Manager

Nov 2003 - Nov 2010

Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Led full system lifecycle from RFP stage to go live including pre-sales, consulting, executive sales, presentations, scope of work, contract negotiation, development, implementation, customer support and post-deployment enhancement requests for large enterprise projects
- ✓ Managed Development, Delivery and Support team of 12 (Developers, Analysts and Testers)
- ✓ Managed diverse group of developers, principal engineers and support staff
- ✓ Led SDLC team and agile transformation from waterfall development
- ✓ Implemented web-based time tracking system to accurately account for time spent on projects and to assist with planning of future projects
- ✓ Provided technical sales support and RFP/RFQ assistance
- ✓ Technologies used: Agile, Jira, Oracle, PL/SQL, C++, .NET, HTML, PowerBuilder, GPS, Google Maps, SAP & CC&B interfaces

Senior System Engineer

March 1996 - Nov 2003

DBMicroware/Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Designed custom workforce management workflow-based software for utilities
- ✓ Created detailed project plans in MS Project with well-defined tasks, milestones, client sign-offs, test cycles, and specifications, which served to communicate project progress to management
- ✓ Developed multi-threaded code resulting in 75% decrease in processing time

Technologies used: Oracle, PL/SQL, SQL Server, Watcom SQL, HTML, PowerBuilder, C++